Why is he on the set?
Quiet on the set.
Why is, please?
First positions, please.
Rolling. Action.
Hello, everyone, and welcome to Director's Cut.
My name is Marco, and I'm joined here with Katherine.
Hey, everyone.
Bill.
Hello.
And Scarlett.
We have a full house today, because we're going to talk about this great movie that,
well, Bill and Katherine are very big fans of, Star Trek.
Yeah.
Well, the new Star Trek, they're actually like nine movies.
movies there are nine movies Wow this is the definitive Star Trek now I guess
they've kind of rebranded is it the definitive no it's not we can talk about
that I agree with you this is the new one the young generation yeah it's like
the prequel yeah exactly because it's done in a good way it's done in a really
good way yeah like just like Transformers or something like that
like we're not talking about Transformers all right so it was a
rebranding well that's it is and it's all new actors new directors I mean it's
very fresh and everyone that was is not a Star Trek fan seemed to like it and to
understand it and in general the consensus was that it was a good film
and everyone was kind of hesitant because like Star Trek you always you
know people don't really say it and it's kind of nerdy it is well this is what we
should say there's a group of people that are hardcore fans of Star Trek what do
you call them they're called Trekkies they have conferences and they dress up
and Deanna Troy often participates in conferences well Deanna Troy still
participates in conferences so what do they conference about characters a plot
yeah like technical specifications they'll be like an episode 0 1 4 5 we
notice you realign the dilithium crystal chamber and away but this is
inconsistent with later episodes when they map out the science of Star Trek
and they talk about yeah consistency and consistency yeah there's like the guy
who created the language Klingon was a linguist who actually took from
different languages and so now there's actually a grammar and a vocabulary for
this language I mean it's real word I can't remember I know one word of Klingon
but I forgot it all right so so there is a whole a whole fan base and the culture
behind Star Trek but on this occasion we're gonna talk briefly about the
movie so the modern version as we said it was great a lot of people liked it
but why do you think that is what do you you mentioned the rebranding of Star
Trek Chris Pine is a hottie yeah I was just gonna say that is that uh is that
Kirk and also the guy from heroes oh yeah I don't know any of these in heroes
he plays a who's that Spock yes Spock on heroes he plays as a guy that has
mental powers that Spock was okay I like I'm not a huge fan of the new Spock
Spock I'm not a huge fan with any of it I'm not even a huge fan of the movie I
think this is what people often say about Trek Trek this is what I heard when
it first came out there's a kind of a set a joke made about this new movie and
it's a nerd talking about Star Trek and it's something like oh that movie that new
Star Trek movie it's totally inconsistent it's terrible blah blah blah but yet
he still goes and he sees it like eight times and so it's it's that kind of
feeling like it's not it doesn't compare to the original ones but it's
cool that they redid it I think and it's cool to see new special effects and stuff
but it's not really true to the original spirit well and I think that's you want
to talk about rebranding that's part of the rebranding process what they did
is they took really hot young actors who some of them are no-name some of
them are kind of like B-list they dress them up in hot clothes and they
threw in a ton of special effects and it was like a slamming summer blockbuster
like action movie but the spirit like Bill says of the old Star Trek is that
effects are bad I mean the state the settings are really kind of poor quality
especially the original the original series like the first season is rough
for special effects because they have these like you know these boulders in
quotes that people get hit with and they're obviously styrofoam and you know
there's pain like coming off yeah but the brilliance is in the acting and like
the overacting and the writing and it's all very kind of yeah I love the whole
history well I guess background I think is what makes it special well like for
example in my case and I know that's this is Scarlett's case as well we've
never really followed Star Trek and we saw this movie it was a little bit
refreshing because you don't have this entire culture that you have to
understand in order to understand the movie you have to see the episode
exactly so you come to the movie you kind of find out a little bit about
Star Trek and it's it's fresh so you actually understand it and it's not
like you walk out of the movie theater when the movie yeah making references to
shows and previous episodes are like what you don't understand I think that's
what's upsetting to hardcore fans is that is that these people can just jump right
in and has it not followed any story from the episodes or that's what's
like going back to the beginning of the when the episode started they
recreated they make a new it's a whole new book what's a whole new storyline
because they introduce some pretty awesome I think this time paradox thing
where people are traveling back in time so actually it's completely different
than how things turn out in in this in the Star Trek universe so they're
creating a new thing so they're they're leaving themselves open to create another
movie well I really appreciate I really appreciated that about this
particular movie because if they followed along the old plot line and
they remade it they would have ticked off everybody all the fans the old
acting you know they would have made everyone really angry so what they did
which was really smart is they created a super super hard to wrap your head
around crazy like string theory approach to like time and and re-plotted the
whole series yeah and that way you can make the other you know the Trekkies
happy by not copying the old series and it's you know it's pretty it's pretty
creative too so I think people can yeah the whole time paradox thing like
you said was pretty creative yeah and well I guess it also uses more modern
theories about like space time in the universe right so that's kind of exactly
and I did spend like four days mapping it out for Amari over at French Pod who
was very confused about how two paths of time could have met
that's basic Star Trek stuff they've already gone back in time they went
back in time the Star Trek 4 yeah all right so why don't you guys set up
what the the clip that we're gonna listen to now this session has been called to
resolve a troubling matter James T Kirk step forward cadet Kirk evidence has
been submitted to this council suggesting that you violated the ethical code of
conduct pursuant to regulation one seven point four three of the Starfleet code
is there anything you care to say before we begin sir yes I believe I have the
right to face my accuser directly step forward please this is commander Spock
he is one of our most distinguished graduates he's programmed the Kobayashi
Maru exam for the last four years commander cadet Kirk you somehow managed
to install and activate a subroutine in the programming code thereby changing the
conditions of the test your point being an academic vernacular you cheated
let me ask you something I think we all know the answer to the test itself is a
cheat isn't it you programmed it to be unwinnable your argument precludes the
possibility of a no-win scenario I don't believe in no-win scenarios then not
only did you violate the rules you also failed to understand the principal lesson
please enlighten me you of all people should know cadet Kirk a captain
cannot cheat death I have all people your father lieutenant George Kirk
assumed command of his vessel before being killed in action did he not I don't
think you like the fact that I beat your test furthermore you have failed to
divine the purpose of the test enlighten me again the purpose is to experience
fear fear in the face of certain death to accept that fear and maintain control
of oneself and one's crew this is a quality expected in every Starfleet
captain well we've got a bunch of these young strapping deads who are in in
training to be in the military essentially Starfleet Academy Starfleet
Academy and they're taking a test and they're taking they've actually take
tests they've taken a test this is the hardest test that's offered at the Star
Fleet Academy it's kind of like for graduating you have to be a shit
Kobayashi Maru and there's a some concern that the main character
captain well Kirk he's not a captain yet has in some way cheated or kind of
stretched the rules and so we're hearing his trial now at school and they're
gonna try and figure out what was going on and whether or not it was
legal all right so let's listen all right we're back so so it seemed like he
didn't really cheat but he just figured out a way to bend the rules of the game
right yeah yeah but at the same time personality he's kind of snarky about it
right but at the same time he claims that the game is also unfair because it's
also like bending the rules of reality in a way well he's saying you're doomed to
failure right right and then he does he just doesn't believe in it so he's he's
got a really strong streak of individualism rebellion rebellion which
which they put in good stark contrast to Spock in this right so Spock was there
and he claims that well he's really upset because obviously he's he's
pretty arrogant of his intelligence right he's a really intelligent being
yeah well he he comes from a place that is not earth and because of this his
people are completely logical they hide all of their emotions they don't
consider they just didn't have any they have them and actually comes out in in
Star Trek the original series in Star Trek the next generation there's some
really weird sex stuff but it's not that they don't have these emotions it's that
they kind of there's a pyramid and they don't believe they mean they're very
base and they don't believe that these should be indulged and so you hide them
you focus on yes it's it's not to be indulged and so they above all else
love logic and that's why this character is sometimes perceived that is
very cold and and overly rational in stark contrast to the main character
Kirk who is completely emotional ego he's he's emotional impulse a cowboy and then
the third character bones is super ego right so he's he's the one or actually
now we've got mess it up so we've got Spock who's ego we've got Kirk who's
like it he's all impulse and we've got bones who's the doctor who's the third
friend who's a little bit older who is super ego he's the kind of balancing act
between the two but he's also like ultra-smart right cuz he's like he's
kind of in the movie he's a drunk but then he's like really a real humanist I
feel like especially through the series you know he's he's kind of always the
voice of this human morality of not always looking at everything from from
the point of logic but but he also kind of tempers Kirk's character because Kirk
like wants to do the right thing going for it and bones sometimes has to pull
him back in and so Kirk and and bones are best friends and bones hates Spock
because he feels that he doesn't have any human humanity to him hmm right and
so there's always this tension between but Spock is half human right
in the movie she makes an appearance yeah that's right she's right at the
beginning really well I know I remember that made a reference to his mom but like
I didn't realize it was a Winona writer yeah that's lame yeah how old how old
are we getting now that Winona writers playing mom mothers and grandmothers
yeah I remember like Beetlejuice yeah that's right all right so all in all
the movie is great I really actually enjoyed the the character who played
Spock because as I said I've only seen him on heroes and he does a pretty good
job on heroes so it was actually refreshing to see him in this movie and
also Eric Bana was the villain what that was really cool
hottie macaw hot speaking of rebranding yeah I mean Klingons they're cool but
they're not the best-looking he was he was well he had welcome yeah addition to
that well although the maker did cover up a lot of that he had like one
forehead slash nose type thing going on yeah yeah it was weird yeah all right so
oh no you guys obviously recommend it right yeah yeah go and watch it I would
watch I know I recommend the whole thing just whole shebang all 35,000
hours as with the other movies there is like a 12 minute sequence where they're
showing the star trip the Starship Enterprise you know where is it's coming
it's like coming out of dock and it's this kind of nerd-tastic slow pan it's
like I don't know it's nerd porn but uh it is pretty cool though I must say and
the USS Enterprise looks really cool yeah that ship all right so go out by
the DVD it's probably out on DVD already or by the blu-ray disc and it's worth it
I actually watched it only about I think it was two or three weeks ago and I
really enjoyed it I wish I would have seen it in the movie theater because
they said it was amazing yeah yeah all right so that's all the time we have for
today be sure to check it out and if you have any questions or comments visit our
website englishpod.com and we'll see you guys next time